You know who I'm envious of?
你们知道我最嫉妒谁吗？
People who work in a job that has to do with their college major.
那些能找到和大学专业对口工作的人。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Journalists who studied journalism,
新闻专业的记者，
engineers who studied engineering.
工程学专业的工程师。
The truth is, these folks are no longer the rule,
事实上，这些人的存在 早已不再是正常情况了，
but the exception.
而成了例外。
A 2010 study found that only a quarter of college graduates
2010年的一个调查显示 只有1/4的大学生，
work in a field that relates to their degree.
在从事和他们大学专业相关的工作。
I graduated with not one but two degrees in biology.
我毕业时拿到了生物学的双学位。
To my parents' dismay, I am neither a doctor nor a scientist.
但令我父母失望的是，我既不是一个医生， 也没有成为一个科学家。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Years of studying DNA replication and photosynthesis
在DNA复制与光合作用上 数年的专心苦读，
did little to prepare me for a career in technology.
对我将来的科技生涯几乎没有帮助。
I had to teach myself everything from sales, marketing, strategy,
我必须从销售，市场营销， 策略开始自学一切本领，
even a little programming, on my own.
甚至连简单的电脑编程，都必须自学。
I had never held the title of Product Manager
在我送简历到 Etsy（电子商务网站）之前，
before I sent my resume in to Etsy.
我从来没当过产品经理。
I had already been turned down by Google and several other firms
我当时十分沮丧， 因为已经被谷歌以及
and was getting frustrated.
其他一些公司屡次拒绝。
The company had recently gone public,
Etsy最近正式上市了，
so as part of my job application,
为了让简历增色，
I read the IPO filings from cover to cover
我把首次公开募股的信息 一行行认真地读，
and built a website from scratch which included my analysis of the business
然后摸索着建立了一个网站，其中 包括一些我对这个公司的分析
and four ideas for new features.
以及四个关于产品特色的新点子。
It turned out the team was actively working on two of those ideas
结果发现这个公司的工作团队 积极地研究了其中两个，
and had seriously considered a third.
并对第三个也进行了慎重考虑。
I got the job.
于是我得到了这份工作。
We all know people who were ignored or overlooked at first
我们都知道有些人 虽然一开始被忽略，
but went on to prove their critics wrong.
但最终用实力证明了他人的错误。
My favorite story?
我最爱的故事是什么呢？
Brian Acton, an engineering manager
Brian Acton, 一个工程经理，
who was rejected by both Twitter and Facebook
在成立whatsApp (聊天软件)之前，
before cofounding WhatsApp,
他同时被谷歌和推特拒绝过，
the mobile messaging platform that would sell for 19 billion dollars.
而现在这个手机软件 平台价值190亿。
The hiring systems we built in the 20th century are failing us
我们在20世纪建立的 招聘系统已经过时了，
and causing us to miss out on people with incredible potential.
这导致我们错失了很多 颇具潜力的人才。
The advances in robotics and machine learning
机器人技术和机器学习的进步
and transforming the way we work,
正在转变我们工作的方式，
automating routine tasks in many occupations
把许多行业的日常事务自动化，
while augmenting and amplifying human labor in others.
从而将人类的劳力转向其他方面。
At this rate, we should all be expecting to do jobs we've never done before
这样下去，我们在 接下来的职业生涯中都要做
for the rest of our careers.
从未做过的工作。
So what are the tools and strategies we need
那么我们需要什么样的 工具以及技巧来辨别那些能够
to identify tomorrow's high performers?
驰骋未来职场的人才呢？
In search for answers, I've consulted with leaders across many sectors,
为了寻得答案，我和 许多部门的领导进行了探讨，
read dozens of reports and research papers
读了很多报告和研究资料，
and conducted some of my own talent experiments.
并分析了我自己的天赋与经历。
My quest is far from over,
我的寻找还远没有结束，
but here are three ideas to take forward.
但有三个要点值得一提。
One: expand your search.
第一：扩展你的搜索范围。
If we only look for talent in the same places we always do --
如果我们每次只去同样的地方 寻找自己的天赋——
gifted child programs, Ivy League schools,
天才少年项目，常青藤名校，
prestigious organizations --
那些盛名远扬的机构——
we're going to get the same results we always have.
那我们只能得到一样的结果。
Baseball was transformed when the cash-strapped Oakland Athletics
奥克兰的运动员队，由于囊中羞涩，
started recruiting players who didn't score highly
只能聘用那些在传统标准， 如打点记录中，
on traditionally valued metrics, like runs batted in,
虽然得分较低， 但却能够帮助队友得分，
but who had the ability to help the team score points
并最终赢得比赛的球员，
and win games.
而这最终导致了棒球的演变。
This idea is taking hold outside of sports.
这道理在体育之外也同样适用。
The Head of Design and Research at Pinterest
Pinterest研究与设计部门的 负责人和我说，
told me that they've built one of the most diverse
他们在硅谷打造了一支，
and high-performing teams in Silicon Valley
全世界最高效， 同时最具分化特色的团队。
because they believe that no one type of person
因为他们相信没有哪一类特定的人
holds a monopoly on talent.
具有垄断性的天赋才能。
They've worked hard to look beyond major tech hubs
他们的眼光超越了核心科技，
and focus on designers' portfolios,
并注重于设计者们的资历，
not their pedigrees.
而不是他们的血统。
Two: hire for performance.
第二：为了效率而雇佣
Inspired by my own job experience,
受到我自己工作经历的启发，
I cofounded a hiring platform called Headlight,
我和别人合建了一个 招聘平台Headlight，
which gives candidates an opportunity to shine.
这个平台给了应聘者们 一个展示自我的机会。
Just as teams have tryouts and plays have auditions,
就好似团队有路演， 乐队有试奏，
candidates should be asked to demonstrate their skills
应聘者在被雇佣之前，
before they're hired.
应该有展示自己技能的机会。
Our clients are benefiting from 85 years of employment research,
从85年的职场雇佣研究资料里， 我们的客户可以看到
which shows that work samples
预测职场成功与否的
are one of the best predictors of success on the job.
最好方式就是工作实例。
If you're hiring a data analyst,
如果你在招聘一个数据分析员，
give them a spreadsheet of historical data and ask them for their key insights.
就给他们一张填满历史数据的 表格并要求他们给出解析。
If you're hiring a marketing manager,
如果你在招聘一个市场经理，
have them plan a launch campaign for a new product.
就让他们计划一场新产品的发布会。
And if you're a candidate, don't wait for an employer to ask.
而如果你是一个应聘者， 别等着老板询问你。
Seek out ways to showcase your unique skills and abilities
寻找能够展现你的独特技巧 与能力的方式，
outside of just the standard resume and cover letter.
而不仅仅是依赖于简历以及推荐信。
Three: get the bigger picture.
第三：着眼全局
I've heard about recruiters who are quick to label a candidate a job-hopper
我见过招聘人员不假思索的给一个 应聘者贴上“跳槽者”的标签，
based on a single short stint on their resume;
仅仅是因为他的简历上 有一项短期的工作；
read about professors who are more likely to ignore identical messages from students
我也听说不少教授会因为 学生的名字属于黑人或亚洲人，
because their name was black or Asian instead of white.
就忽视他们发送的和 白人学生一模一样的消息。
I was almost put on a special needs track as a child.
我小时候几乎被当成有 “特殊需要”的孩子。
A month into kindergarten,
进入幼儿园一个月后，
my teacher wrote a page-long memo
我的老师记录了一整页的笔记，
noting that I was impulsive,
上面写着我极易冲动，
had a short attention span,
注意力难以集中，
and despite my wonderful curiosity,
虽然拥有极大的好奇心，
I was exhausting to work with.
但却是一个使人筋疲力尽的孩子。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
The principal asked my parents into a meeting,
校长叫我的家长们来开会，
asked my mother if there had been complications at birth
问我妈生我的时候 有没有遇到什么困难，
and suggested I meet with a school psychologist.
还建议我去看学校的心理医生。
My father saw what was happening
我的父亲明白了是怎么一回事，
and quickly explained our family situation.
并简短的解释了我们家的情况。
As recent immigrants, we lived in the attic
作为刚刚移民的家庭，
of a home that cared for adults with mental disabilities.
我们住在一家老年 康复中心的阁楼里。
My parents worked nights to make ends meet,
我的父母为了维持生计 整日整夜工作，
and I had little opportunity to spend time with kids my own age.
而我也几乎没有和 同龄孩子玩耍的机会。
Is it really a surprise that an understimulated five-year-old boy
对于一个交际经验不足，又刚刚独处了 整整一个夏天的五岁小男孩来说，
might be a little excited in a kindergarten classroom
在幼儿园的教室里 显得有些过度兴奋，
after an entire summer by himself?
也许不显得那么令人惊讶吧？
Until we get a holistic view of someone,
在我们没有看到一个人 完整的一面的时候，
our judgment of them will always be flawed.
我们对他的评判总是有失偏颇的。
Let's stop equating experience with ability,
让我们别再把经历和能力划等号，
credentials with competence.
也别把文凭和竞争力划等号。
Let's stop settling for the safe, familiar choice
让我们不要再一昧的做出 安全，熟悉的选择，
and leave the door open for someone who could be amazing.
而是把机会给予那些 能够让你眼前一亮的人。
We need employers to let go of outdated hiring practices
我们需要让雇主们放弃 那些过时的雇佣政策，
and embrace new ways of identifying and cultivating talent,
去拥抱那些定义和 培养天赋的新方法，
and candidates can help by learning to tell their story
而求职者们也可以通过 用强势且引人注目的方式，
in powerful and compelling ways.
来讲述自己的人生故事。
We could live in a world where people are seen for what they're truly capable of
我们会生活在全新的世界里，在那里 人们的潜力将有望被完全激发，
and have the opportunity to realize their full potential.
人人都能够做自己真正胜任的工作。
So let's go out and build it.
所以让我们一起携手建造这个世界吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）